Akifumi Wachi

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie primarily in reinforcement learning, and span the entire theory-to-application spectrum from foundational advances all the way to deployment in real systems. I am particularly enthusiastic about conducting both empirical and theoretical studies that contribute to the improvement of reinforcement learning, ensuring its efficacy, safety, and reliability in practical applications.

Work Experience

Chief Research Scientist Oct 2023 - present

LY Corporation

Senior Research Scientist Sep 2022 - Sep 2023

LINE Corporation

Research Scientist Apr 2018 - Aug 2022

IBM Research AI

EDUCATION

Mar 2021 Ph.D. in Computer Science at University of Tsukuba

Mar 2018 M.S. in Aeronautics and Astronautics at University of Tokyo

Mar 2016 B.S. in Aeronautics and Astronautics at University of Tokyo

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. <u>Akifumi Wachi</u>, Xun Shen, Yanan Sui, "A Survey of Constraint Formulations in Safe Reinforcement Learning" International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), Survey Track, 2024.
- 2. <u>Akifumi Wachi</u>, Wataru Hashimoto, Kazumune Hashimoto, "Long-term Safe Reinforcement Learning with Binary Feedback" AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2024.
- 3. Xun Shen, <u>Akifumi Wachi</u>, Wataru Hashimoto, Kazumune Hashimoto, Shigemasa Takai "Safe Reinforcement Learning Using Model Predictive Control with Probabilistic Control Barrier Function" American Control Conference (ACC), 2024.
- 4. <u>Akifumi Wachi</u>, Wataru Hashimoto, Xun Shen, Kazumune Hashimoto, "Safe Exploration in Reinforcement Learning: A Generalized Formulation and Algorithms" Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023.
- 5. <u>Akifumi Wachi</u>, Yunyue Wei, Yanan Sui, "Safe Policy Optimization with Local Generalized Linear Function Approximations" Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021.
- 6. Ran Iwamoto, Ryosuke Kohita, <u>Akifumi Wachi</u>, "Polar Embedding" The SIGNLL Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL), 2021.
- Daiki Kimura, Masaki Ono, Subhajit Chaudhury, Ryosuke Kohita, <u>Akifumi Wachi</u>, Don Joven Agravante, Michiaki Tatsubori, Asim Munawar, Alexander Gray, "Neuro-Symbolic Reinforcement Learning with First-Order Logic" Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), Short paper, 2021.
- 8. Ryosuke Kohita, Akifumi Wachi, Daiki Kimura, Subhajit Chaudhury, Michiaki Tatsubori, Asim Mu-

- nawar, "Language-based General Action Template for Reinforcement Learning Agents" Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), Findings, 2021.
- Ryosuke Kohita, <u>Akifumi Wachi</u>, Yang Zhao, Ryuki Tachibana, "Q-learning with Language Model for Edit-based Unsupervised Summarization" Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020
- 10. <u>A. Wachi</u>, Y. Sui, "Safe Reinforcement Learning in Constrained Markov Decision Processes", International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020
- 11. <u>A. Wachi</u>, "Failure-Scenario Maker for Rule-based Agent using Multi-agent Adversarial Reinforcement Learning and its Application to Autonomous Driving", International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2019
- 12. <u>A. Wachi, Y. Sui, Y. Yue, M. Ono, "Safe Exploration and Optimization of Constrained MDPs using Gaussian Processes"</u>, AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2018
- 13. R. Sakagami, R. Takahashi, <u>A. Wachi</u>, Y. Koshiro, H. Maezawa, Y. Kasai, S. Nakasuka, "Integral Design Method for Simple and Small Mars Lander System Using Membrane Aeroshell", Acta Astronautica.
- 14. <u>A. Wachi</u>, R. Takahashi, R. Sakagami, Y. Koshiro, Y. Kasai, S. Nakasuka, "Feasibility Study for Mars Landing with Small Space Probe", AIAA SPACE and Astronautics Forum and Exposition (2017 AIAA SPACE Forum), 2017.
- 15. <u>A. Wachi</u>, "Low-Thrust Trajectory Design to Improve Overall Mission Success Probability Incorporating Target Changes in Case of Engine Failures", 31st International Symposium on Space Technology and Science (ISTS), 2017. **Nominated to Best Student Paper Award: First Prize (General Chairperson Award)**
- 16. <u>A. Wachi</u>, N. Ozaki, S. Nakasuka, "Fault-Tolerant Low-Thrust Trajectory Design with Backups for Multiple Targets", 20th IFAC Symposium on Automatic Control in Aerospace (ACA), 2016. **Nominated to the Best Student Paper Award: First Prize.**

PATENTS

I have over 10 filed patents which can be found here:

• https://patents.justia.com/search?q=akifumi+wachi

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Conference Reviewing (Program Committee Member)

- ICML 2021 2024
- NeurIPS 2021 2023
- ICLR 2022 2024
- AISTATS 2024
- IJCAI 2020 2024
- AAAI 2020 2024
- ACL 2020 2023
- EMNLP 2020

Journal Reviewing

- ACM Transactions on Evolutionary Learning and Optimization (Associate Editor)
- IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence

Awards

- Dean's Award (second prize), from Faculty of Engineering, The University of Tokyo, 2018
- Best Student Paper Award, First Prize (General Chairperson Award), Joint Conference: 31st ISTS, 26th ISSFD, and 8th NSAT, 2017, http://www.ists.or.jp/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/31_Prize-List.pdf
- Best Student Paper Award (First Prize), IFAC Symposium on Automatic Control in Aerospace (ACA), 2016, http://aca2016.ngcaerospace.com/studentaward.php

Fellowship

- Financial support to participate in Thirty-second AAAI conference on Artificial Intelligence by Society for Promotion of Space Science (SPSS), \$1.5K, February, 2018
- Financial support to participate in International Astronautical Congress (IAC) by the Japan Society for Aeronautical and Space Sciences (JSASS), \$2.5K, September, 2017
- Go Global Scholarships 2016 Short Study Abroad Scholarships: the University of Tokyo, \$1K/month, 3 months, 2016
- Fellowship of the Leading Graduates Schools Program: Global Leader Program for Social Design and Management by the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology in Japan, \$1K/month, 1 year, 2016
- Financial support to visit California Institute of Technology (Caltech) and NASA/JPL by the University of Tokyo, \$1.0K, February, 2014

Last updated: May 3, 2024